Mom, I'm scared
أمي، أنا خائف
I'm telling you all
أقول لكم كل شيء
We are Yida Real Estate
نحن شركة ييدا للعقارات
Our boss is Zheng Nanfeng
رئيسنا هو تشنغ نانفنغ
If any of you refuse to cooperate with relocation
إذا رفض أي منكم التعاون في عملية النقل
I'll make you pay dearly
سأجعلك تدفع ثمناً باهظاً
Go
يذهب
Today's task
مهمة اليوم
All holdouts
جميع العروض
Must be won over
يجب كسبه
Yes
نعم
Open up, anyone?
هل من أحد يرغب في التحدث؟
You... you... like this...
أنتَ... أنتَ... هكذا...
Fine
بخير
Are you kidding me?
هل تمزح معي؟
Hello, sir
أهلاً سيدي
I'm Zheng Nanfeng
أنا تشنغ نانفنغ
You're here for relocation, right?
أنت هنا من أجل الانتقال، أليس كذلك؟
Yes
نعم
I represent Yida Real Estate
أنا أمثل شركة ييدا للعقارات
Here to discuss relocation matters
نحن هنا لمناقشة مسائل الانتقال.
Go, all of you, go
انطلقوا جميعاً، انطلقوا
I won't move even if I die
لن أتحرك حتى لو مت
Hey, hey, hey
هي، هي، هي
Uncle, we're from Yida Real Estate
يا عمي، نحن من شركة ييدا للعقارات
Hey, hey
مرحباً، مرحباً
Sorry
آسف
Get lost, now!
انصرف الآن!
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Don't, don't
لا تفعل، لا تفعل
Don't be so aggressive
لا تكن عدوانياً جداً
Nanfeng
نانفينج
As soon as they hear we're Yida Real Estate
بمجرد أن يسمعوا أننا شركة ييدا للعقارات
They refuse to discuss anything
يرفضون مناقشة أي شيء
They just kick us out
يطردوننا ببساطة
We didn't do anything
لم نفعل أي شيء
It is a bit strange
الأمر غريب بعض الشيء
Let's go ask the village chief
لنذهب ونسأل رئيس القرية
Let's go
دعنا نذهب
Forced demolition
الهدم القسري
It wasn't me
لم أكن أنا
Village chief
رئيس القرية
We only arrived today
لقد وصلنا اليوم فقط
How could anyone...
كيف يمكن لأي شخص...
have come yesterday to force a demolition?
هل جاؤوا أمس لإجبارهم على الهدم؟
Yeah
نعم
No matter what you say
مهما قلت
It was definitely your people yesterday
كان أهلك بالتأكيد بالأمس
who threatened them
الذين هددوهم
Otherwise they wouldn't be
وإلا لما كانوا موجودين
treating you with this attitude
معاملتك بهذه الطريقة
It must be Xie Rong and her people
لا بد أن يكون ذلك من شي رونغ وشعبها
Village chief
رئيس القرية
I, Zheng Nanfeng, guarantee this on my honor
أنا، تشنغ نانفنغ، أضمن هذا بشرفي
The three of us came today
لقد حضرنا نحن الثلاثة اليوم
to discuss with everyone
للمناقشة مع الجميع
the relocation compensation matter
مسألة التعويض عن الانتقال
Forced demolition has nothing to do with us
الهدم القسري لا علاقة لنا به
Of course, you can choose not to believe
بالطبع، يمكنك اختيار عدم التصديق
But commercial housing construction
لكن بناء المساكن التجارية
is a national development trend
هو اتجاه تنموي وطني
We can't let the village's growth stall
لا يمكننا السماح بتوقف نمو القرية
Exactly
بالضبط
Go to the west end of the village and find Uncle Miao
اذهب إلى الطرف الغربي من القرية وابحث عن العم مياو
He's the Miao family's patriarch
هو رب أسرة مياو
and the head of these holdouts
ورئيس هؤلاء الممتنعين
If you can persuade him
إذا استطعت إقناعه
the others will agree
سيوافق الآخرون
But I have to warn you first
لكن عليّ أن أحذرك أولاً
Uncle Miao has a very odd temper
يتمتع العم مياو بمزاج غريب للغاية
You should be careful
يجب أن تكون حذرا
Feng, this is it
فينغ، هذا هو الأمر
Uncle Miao
العم مياو
Who are you looking for?
من تبحث عنه؟
Uncle Miao, I'm Zheng Nanfeng from Yida Real Estate
عم مياو، أنا زينج نانفينج من شركة ييدا العقارية
Zheng Nanfeng, right?
تشنغ نانفنغ، أليس كذلك؟
Get lost
اغرب عن وجهي
This old man...
هذا الرجل العجوز...
Uncle, we're a legitimate company
يا عمي، نحن شركة شرعية
Our company's relocation compensation is approved
تمت الموافقة على تعويضات الانتقال التي تقدمها شركتنا
It's over 100,000
إنها أكثر من 100 ألف
You little punks
يا صغار الأوغاد
Ganging up to mess with people, huh?
يتجمعون لإيذاء الناس، أليس كذلك؟
I'll risk my old life; I won't let you succeed
سأخاطر بحياتي السابقة؛ لن أدعك تنجح
Let alone over 100,000
ناهيك عن أكثر من 100 ألف
Even 10,000,000 or 100,000,000, I won't agree
حتى لو كان العدد 10 ملايين أو 100 مليون، فلن أوافق
Wait, Uncle
انتظر يا عمي
Get lost, or I'll stab you to death
ابتعد عني، وإلا سأطعنك حتى الموت
How did it go?
كيف سارت الأمور؟
No go, huh?
لا جدوى، أليس كذلك؟
I knew it wouldn't work.
كنت أعرف أنها لن تنجح.
They'll kick us out for sure.
سيطردوننا بالتأكيد.
It's already good we didn't even hit him.
من الجيد أننا لم نصبه حتى.
You can't handle such an ordinary holdout.
لا يمكنك التعامل مع هذا الشخص العادي الذي يرفض الاستسلام.
You think I came today to negotiate with him?
أتظن أنني جئت اليوم لأتفاوض معه؟
Take a look.
ألقِ نظرة.
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
Didn't you see?
ألم ترَ؟
Are the ornaments here all related to Feng Shui?
هل جميع الزخارف هنا مرتبطة بفنغ شوي؟
What does that tell you?
ماذا يعني ذلك بالنسبة لك؟
It means he believes in Feng Shui.
هذا يعني أنه يؤمن بفنغ شوي.
Oh.
أوه.
So?
لذا؟
Whoa, Master.
يا سيدي، مهلاً.
Make way, make way.
أفسحوا الطريق، أفسحوا الطريق.
Master, slow down.
يا سيدي، تمهل.
Slow down, slow down, slow down.
خفف السرعة، خفف السرعة، خفف السرعة.
Watch your step.
انتبه لخطواتك.
Master, slow down, okay.
يا سيدي، تمهل، حسناً.
This spot has an open frontage.
يتميز هذا الموقع بواجهة مفتوحة.
Sacred mountains guard both sides.
الجبال المقدسة تحمي كلا الجانبين.
Good place.
أماكن جيدة.
If you plan to develop this area,
إذا كنت تخطط لتطوير هذه المنطقة،
Dig a channel here.
احفر قناة هنا.
It must have a bend.
لا بد أن يكون به انحناء.
The inlet should be big.
يجب أن يكون المدخل كبيرًا.
The outlet should be small.
يجب أن يكون المخرج صغيرًا.
Two channels here
قناتان هنا
converge into a vortex.
تتقارب لتشكل دوامة.
This is the Hanging Water Treasure Basin.
هذا هو حوض كنز المياه المعلق.
Guarantees you'll make money hand over fist.
يضمن لك هذا البرنامج ربحاً وفيراً.
Well then, Master,
حسناً يا سيدي،
Where should this bend be dug?
أين ينبغي حفر هذا المنحنى؟
Have the two channels form an angle.
اجعل القناتين تشكلان زاوية.
That way its sha energy will shoot straight to...
وبهذه الطريقة، ستنطلق طاقة "شا" مباشرة إلى...
May I ask,
هل لي أن أسأل؟
can people live here?
هل يستطيع الناس العيش هنا؟
Master.
يتقن.
This is Uncle Miao's house.
هذا منزل العم مياو.
And this is my house.
وهذا بيتي.
Will the layout you just mentioned affect our home?
هل سيؤثر التصميم الذي ذكرته للتو على منزلنا؟
Hey, Uncle Miao,
مرحباً يا عم مياو،
You can't disrupt the Master's work.
لا يمكنك تعطيل عمل المعلم.
Meeting is fate.
اللقاء قدر.
I'll also take a look for Uncle Miao.
سأبحث أيضاً عن العم مياو.
Ah.
آه.
This guy does Feng Shui.
هذا الرجل خبير في فنغ شوي.
Darn it
اللعنة
Master
يتقن
As for this,
أما بخصوص هذا،
I can't deal with it
لا أستطيع التعامل مع ذلك
Is our home's Feng Shui bad?
هل فنغ شوي منزلنا سيء؟
Sir, your home's Feng Shui is excellent
سيدي، فنغ شوي منزلك ممتاز
It could keep you living to one hundred
قد يساعدك ذلك على العيش حتى سن المئة.
But with the demolition around you,
لكن مع عمليات الهدم التي تحيط بك،
it broke your whole setup
لقد أدى ذلك إلى تعطيل نظامك بالكامل
Then what should we do?
إذن ماذا ينبغي علينا أن نفعل؟
Now that it's come to this,
والآن وقد وصل الأمر إلى هذا الحد،
Take my advice,
خذ بنصيحتي،
Move out
الانتقال من المنزل
Ah, moving means a loss
آه، الانتقال يعني خسارة
That's over a hundred thousand
هذا أكثر من مائة ألف
Oh
أوه
So you teamed up to scam me
إذن تعاونتم للاحتيال عليّ
I knew you had bad intentions
كنت أعلم أن لديك نوايا سيئة
Get lost!
اغرب عن وجهي!
Oh, oh, oh!
أوه، أوه، أوه!
Master
يتقن
Uncle Miao doesn't know how to talk
العم مياو لا يعرف كيف يتحدث
Please don't take it to heart
أرجوك لا تأخذ الأمر على محمل الجد
Act
يمثل
Keep acting
استمر في التمثيل
No problem
لا مشكلة
It's human nature
إنها طبيعة الإنسان
Well, with this kind of thing,
حسناً، مع هذا النوع من الأشياء،
It works if you believe
ينجح الأمر إذا كنت تؤمن به.
Ah
آه
Sir,
سيد،
Have you been dizzy and feverish lately?
هل شعرت بالدوار والحمى مؤخراً؟
You often have nightmares at night
غالباً ما تراودك الكوابيس ليلاً
Your health is much worse than before
صحتك أسوأ بكثير مما كانت عليه من قبل
How do you know about that?
كيف عرفت ذلك؟
This is the Feng Shui around you shifting,
هذا هو فنغ شوي المحيط بك يتغير،
and it shows on you as a result
وينعكس ذلك عليك نتيجة لذلك
This can't be solved just by moving out
لا يمكن حل هذه المشكلة بمجرد الانتقال من المنزل
Master, that's exactly my situation right now
يا سيدي، هذا هو وضعي بالضبط الآن
Can you find a way to break it?
هل يمكنك إيجاد طريقة لكسرها؟
Sure, sure
بالتأكيد، بالتأكيد
Come, sir
تفضل يا سيدي
Look at your doorway
انظر إلى مدخل منزلك
Follow me
تابعني
Oh no
يا إلهي
Xie Rong
شيه رونغ
Uncle Miao is about to sign a contract with Zheng Nanfeng
يستعد العم مياو لتوقيع عقد مع تشنغ نانفنغ
Impossible
مستحيل
How did he change Uncle Miao's mind so fast?
كيف استطاع تغيير رأي العم مياو بهذه السرعة؟
They seem to have brought in some master
يبدو أنهم استعانوا ببعض الخبراء
Said there's a problem with the Feng Shui at Uncle Miao's home
قال إن هناك مشكلة في فنغ شوي في منزل العم مياو
Told him to move out right away
طلبت منه أن يغادر على الفور
Uncle Miao really believes in that
العم مياو يؤمن بذلك حقاً
Feng Shui Master
سيد فنغ شوي
Mm
مم
Checking Feng Shui
التحقق من فنغ شوي
This guy has some skills
هذا الرجل لديه بعض المهارات
He thought along the same lines as me
كان يفكر بنفس الطريقة التي أفكر بها
Xie Rong
شيه رونغ
So what should we do next?
إذن، ما الذي يجب أن نفعله بعد ذلك؟
Sir, you're almost here, right?
سيدي، أنت على وشك الوصول، أليس كذلك؟
Okay
تمام
We have been waiting for you for a long time
لقد كنا ننتظرك لفترة طويلة
Xie Rong
شيه رونغ
You were prepared in advance
لقد كنت مستعداً مسبقاً
Who is impersonating the master?
من ينتحل شخصية المعلم؟
Warriors, assemble before me!
أيها المحاربون، اجتمعوا أمامي!
Burning Cloud
سحابة مشتعلة
Split Sky-Piercing Assault of the Nine Bends
هجوم خارق للسماء من الانحناءات التسعة
Five Elements Sha Neutralization
معادلة العناصر الخمسة شا
Elder
شيخ
This blocks your home's nine-bend incoming water
هذا يعيق تدفق المياه الداخلة إلى منزلك عبر الأنابيب التسعة المنحنية
and the Sha energy in the middle
وطاقة شا في المنتصف
I have broken it for you
لقد كسرتها من أجلك
This is the Black Dragon King from the port city
هذا هو ملك التنين الأسود من المدينة الساحلية
Master Ma
المعلم ما
What are you waiting for?
ماذا تنتظر؟
Kneel and bow!
اركع وانحنِ!
You are the Black Dragon King
أنت ملك التنين الأسود
Thank you, Black Dragon King
شكراً لك، ملك التنين الأسود
Thank you, Divine One
شكراً لك يا إلهي
Please save me
أرجوك أنقذني
Darn it
اللعنة
Xie Rong sent a real Master to wreck the place
أرسل شي رونغ سيدًا حقيقيًا لتدمير المكان
But why have I never heard of such a person?
لكن لماذا لم أسمع قط عن شخص كهذا؟
We have not heard of him either
لم نسمع عنه أيضاً
Recently, two con artists came to Haicheng
في الآونة الأخيرة، جاء اثنان من المحتالين إلى هايتشنغ
Posing as Feng Shui experts to swindle people
انتحال صفة خبراء في فنغ شوي للاحتيال على الناس
Everyone, keep your eyes open
أيها الجميع، ابقوا أعينكم مفتوحة
Scammers!
محتالون!
Do not lightly believe their words
لا تصدق كلامهم بسهولة
Losing money is minor
خسارة المال أمر بسيط
If the Feng Shui is ruined, your life will be short
إذا ساءت الأمور وفقًا لمبادئ فنغ شوي، فسيكون عمرك قصيرًا.
You two scammers
أنتما محتالان
Get out, now
اخرج الآن
Go!
يذهب!
So you are the Black Dragon King?
إذن أنت ملك التنين الأسود؟
My formation follows Dao and nature
تكويني يتبع الداو والطبيعة
It is granted by Heaven and Earth
إنها هبة من السماء والأرض
Not something you can break just by declaring it
ليس شيئًا يمكنك كسره بمجرد إعلانه
This Black Dragon King's Burning Cloud
سحابة اللهب الخاصة بملك التنين الأسود
will backfire
سوف يأتي بنتائج عكسية
This miasma is the backlash
هذا الضباب هو رد الفعل العكسي
This backlash will not only snuff out divine guardians
لن تؤدي هذه الردة العنيفة إلى إخماد الحراس الإلهيين فحسب.
In the end
في النهاية
it will slowly move onto humans
سينتقل ببطء إلى البشر
Darn you
تباً لك
You are lying
أنت تكذب
Time is pressing
الوقت يضغط
We must remove it at once
يجب علينا إزالته على الفور
Move aside
ابتعدوا جانباً
Break!
استراحة!
Uncle Miao, look again
العم مياو، انظر مرة أخرى
The miasma the Black Dragon King summoned
المياسما التي استدعاها ملك التنين الأسود
I have already removed it for you
لقد قمت بإزالته بالفعل من أجلك
You brats dare to spout wild boasts
يا لكم من صغار وقحين، تجرؤون على التباهي بأشياء جامحة!
Do you dare to battle me?
هل تجرؤ على مواجهتي؟
Spare me your petty little tricks
كفى حيلك التافهة
I advise you
أنصحك
Go back where you came from
ارجع من حيث أتيت
I miss you
أفتقدك
Whenever dusk falls
كلما حل الغسق
the night breeze rises
نسيم الليل يهب
I miss you
أفتقدك
the answer to life's riddle
إجابة لغز الحياة
Try not to look too closely
حاول ألا تنظر عن كثب
Close your eyes
أغمض عينيك
Do not respond
لا ترد
The night breeze blows and blows
تهب نسائم الليل وتهب.
Go with the wind
انطلق مع الريح
Tonight, children, do not cry in secret
الليلة يا أطفال، لا تبكوا سراً
Do not cry in secret
لا تبكِ في السر
The night breeze blows and blows
تهب نسائم الليل وتهب.
Go with the wind
انطلق مع الريح
As night falls with stars
مع حلول الليل وظهور النجوم
Gently fall asleep
نم بهدوء
Blow, night breeze
هبّي يا نسيم الليل